#### CATHERINE WANJIRU NDUNG'U

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth: 03/09/1967

Postal Address: 10388-00200 Nairobi Mobile No: + 254 0725 668 811

E-mail: CNdung'u@kplc.co.ke

#### **PROFILE**

A long standing passion in continuous improvement processes gives me the determination and confidence to succeed in Quality Management Systems. I am a responsible, focused, intelligent, open-minded individual with proven track record in design and implementation of quality management systems. In addition, I have adequate experience with the ability to work well- both independently, in a team and as a team leader.

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

A competent, highly motivated leader and team player willing to work in a Qaulity Assurance function where, skill and experience can be put to good use in an environment where hard work produces solid end-results.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Proven leadership skills and ability to work in a team
- Ability to quickly learn new skills and grasp new constructs
- Good communicator with excellent interpersonal and training skills
- Ability to deliver within tight reporting deadlines.
- Ability to analyse the available information and make factual decisions
- Strong attention to details

## EXPERIENCE AND EMPLOYMENT

March 2016 to date Employer: **KPLC** 

Position: Chief Officer, Quality Management Systems

Roles and responsibilities - Chief Officer, Quality Management Systems

- Aligning programmes on quality management systems with the business objectives
- Establishing, documenting, implementing and maintaining quality management systems in the company
- Reviewing and continuously improving quality management systems in the company
- Planning and conducting internal quality audits as per the requirements of the quality management systems
- Planning and implementing suitable training programs on quality management sytems to increase awareness, motivation and involvement
- Creating awareness of customer requirements throughout the company to enhance customer satisfaction
- Liaising with the certification body for external quality audits and certification purposes

- Advising top management on the status of the quality management system and areas of improvement
- Liaising with internal quality auditors, regional management representatives and auditees in resolving the observed non-conformities and continuously improving quality management systems in the company

January 2012 to date Employer: KPLC

Position: Senior Quality Assurance Officer

#### Roles and responsibilities - Senior Quality Assurance Officer

- Aligning programmes on quality management systems with the business objectives
- Documenting, implementing and maintaining quality management systems in the company
- Planning and conducting internal quality audits as per the requirements of the quality management systems
- Planning and implementing suitable training programs on quality management sytems to increase awareness, motivation and involvement
- Ensuring utilisation of IT systems in supporting the implementation and management of quality management systems
- Liaising with internal quality auditors, regional management representatives and auditees in resolving the observed non-conformities and continuously improving quality management systems in the company

July 2008 to January 2012 Employer: KPLC

Position: Quality Assurance Officer I

#### Roles and responsibilities – Quality Assurance Officer I

- Establishing, documenting, implementing and maintaining quality management systems in the company
- Reviewing and continuously improving quality management systems in the company
- Planning and conducting internal quality audits as per the requirements of the quality management system
- Planning and implementing suitable training programs on quality management sytems to increase awareness, motivation and involvement
- Maintaining the quality management records
- Advising top management on the status of the quality management system and areas of improvement

June 2006 – July 2008 Employer: **KPLC** 

Position: Internal Auditor II, Information Systems

Roles and responsibilities - Internal Auditor II, Information Systems

- Perform internal audits that evaluate computerized systems and internal controls and provide assurance that internal controls in business processing systems, technical infrastructure, and IT organization are effective and efficient.
- Examine computer processes and systems and provide management with recommendations for improvements to policies, procedures, and practices.
- Identify risks, assess controls, and recommend internal control improvements across a wide variety of IT processes and technology.
- Prepare audit reports for senior management that clearly and concisely communicate control issues, business impact, and management action plans.
- Establish and maintain a working relationship with IT by participating in the department's liaison program.
- Participate in the development of major new computerized systems
- Assist the other internal audit groups in their computerized needs.

October 1996 – May 2006 Employer: Kenya Bureau of Standards (KEBs)

Position: **Head of IT operations** 

### Roles and responsibilities – **Head of IT operations**

- ISO 9001: 2008 Standard trainer

ISO 9001: 2008 Auditor

- Expanding the scope of the certification department to include information security management system (ISMS ISO 27001) certification scheme
- ICT department Management Representative in the Quality Management System
- Implementation of the quality system in the ICT department
- Preparation of the departmental procedures and quality manual
- Development and maintenance of KEBS website
- User support
- Supervision of the staff in the ICT department
- End-user training
- Internet connectivity and administration
- Procurement of IT equipment and services
- Security assessment and implementation
- Any other duties as may be assigned by the Management.

### Other Duties included:

- A sitting member and secretary to the ICT departmental meetings

- A sitting member and assistant secretary of the Kenya Bureau of Standards Corruption Prevention Committee
- A sitting member to the KEBS committee to harmonise scheme of service
- A sitting member to the Kenya Bureau of Standards Tenders Evaluation Committee

October 1990 – September 1996 Employer: Kenya Polytechnic

Position: Lecturer

# **EDUCATION**

2009 -	Nairobi University
	- Course: PhD in Business Administration
	- Area of Specialization: Operations Management
2003 - 2004:	Strathmore University
	- Course: Certified Information Systems Auditor (CISA)
2002 – 2004:	Nairobi University
	- Course: MSc. Information Systems
	- Area of Specialization: Information Systems Management
1994 – 1996:	Intellect Computer Services
	- Course: Higher Diploma Computer Science (IMIS)
1987 - 1990:	Nairobi University
	- Course: Bachelor of Science (General)
	- Area of Specialization: Mathematics & Chemistry
1985 - 1986:	Mukumu Girls High School
	-Course: A levels
	- Area of Specialization: Mathematics, Physics & Chemistry
1981 - 1984:	Mary Mount Secondary School
	- Qualifications: KCE Division 1

# **Membership in Professional Societies:**

- 1. Information Systems Audit and Control Association (ISACA) Certified Information Systems Auditor (CISA)
- 2. Kenya Bureau of Standards Certification Body Quality Management Systems Auditor
- 3. National Quality Instute (NQI) Quality Management Systems Trainer/Consultant
- 4. PTAK Professional Trainer Association of Kenya Quality Management Systems Trainer

## **Key Qualifications:**

Have trained, audited or consulted on QMS in the following firms among others:

- Kenya Bureau of Standards
- Kenya Medical Training College
- Kenya Power & Lighting
- Kenya Sugar Board
- Lake Victoria North Water Services Board
- Nairobi Water Services Company
- National Hospital Insurance Fund
- Nzoia Sugar Company
- Ewaso Ng'iro South Development Authority
- Commission of Higher Education
- Kenya Literature Bureau
- Nkabune Technical Training Institute
- Ministry of Labour
- Ministry of Information
- Ministry of Immigration and Registration of Persons
- Kabianga University
- Nyeri Technical Training Institute
- Mathenge Technical Training Institute
- Machakos University College
- Kenya Film Commission
- Chalbi Business Solutions
- Kenya National Trading Corporation
- Competition Authority of Kenya
- Bulto Supplies & Transporters

#### OTHER TRAININGS

- Certified Lean six Sigma Foundation Green Belt (UK)
- Program for Quality Management (Japan)
- Lead Auditor ISO 50001:2011- Energy Management Systems
- Lead Auditor ISO 9001:2008 Quality Management Systems
- Trainer of Trainers Quality Management Systems
- ISO 9001:2015 Transition
- ISO 9001:2015 Lead Auditor Training

# OTHER RESPONSIBILITIES AND HOBBIES:

- Mentoring
- Travelling
- Participating in various local marathons.
- Doing social voluntary work

## **REFERENCES:**

Ms. Carolyn Outa
 Chief Manager, Certification Department
 Kenya Bureau of Standards
 P.O. Box 54974 - 00200

Nairobi

Tel: +254 20 6948000

 Prof Isaac Mbeche University of Nairobi Dean, Students Welfare P.O. Box 30197 – 00200 Nairobi

Tel: +254 20 318262

 Dr. Eng. Peter Kimemia Manager, Standards Kenya Power and Lighting Co. P.O. Box 30099 - 00100 Nairobi

Tel: +254 20 3201416